# MATTHEW SCHNEBLE

Seattle WA (949) 836-8089

I am an experienced Project/Program Manager with experience in various industries. I am an energized and committed worker who ensures projects are delivered on time and on budget under ever changing requirements and environments. I am used to working with various tools to best serve the project.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **AUGUST 2015 - MAY 2015**

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST, AVANADE**

Acted as a key team member on over 10 projects in various roles and industries. Selected experience below

#### FEBRUARY 2022 - JANUARY 2023

#### PROJECT OPERATIONS MANAGER, LARGE NATIONAL RETAILER

- Responsible for managing the \$12M+ project budget and ensuring on budget delivery
- Responsible for the resource plan consisting of over 40 employees between onshore and offshore teams
- Responsible for the onboarding and offboarding of resources, as well as managing access control to various internal project sites
- Worked with 5 different workstreams to coordinate upcoming resource needs, prioritizing based on constantly changing requirements
- Coordinated and conducted project replanning due to sudden scope change and actively managed scope moving forward
- Developed end to end business processes and updated processes to ensure efficiency
- Directly managed 2 onshore and 2 offshore resources
- Delivered monthly financial and resourcing updates to executive stakeholders
- Managed and Administered Azure Dev Ops and SharePoint sites for the project
- Generated reports from custom queries on Azure Dev Ops and translated into PowerBI dashbaords

#### **APRIL 2021 – JANUARY 2022**

#### TECHNICAL PROGRAM MANAGER, GLOBAL TECHNOLOGY COMPANY

- Responsible for managing feature updates from idea generation through delivery
- Worked with numerous onshore and offshore team members across various teams to scope, triage, build, debug and deliver features in a SCRUM environment
- Ran sprint planning and retrospectives for team
- Developed business requirements and translated into actionable user stories
- Managed deliveries via SCRUM board in Azure Dev Ops
- Created and delivered project updates to program leadership
- Ensured features met compliance and accessibility standards
- Utilized PowerBI to create dashboards and visualizations

#### **SEPTEMBER 2019 – MARCH 2021**

## PROGRAM MANAGER, GLOBAL TECHNOLOGY COMPANY

- Developed new program from scratch generating between \$4M \$5M revenue per year
- Created all relevant end to end business processes, from initial lead generation through completion of contract
- Interviewed over 300 people, and performance management/people ownership including reviews and discipline, for team of 20-25
- Coordinated regular meetings with leads across 9 different teams in 2 time zones to determine upcoming resource needs and review individual performance
- Coordinated and led bi-monthly meetings with client program leadership to determine upcoming needs
- Responsible for ensuring accuracy in monthly reporting and billing
- Directly managed one nearshore resource
- Created and developed dashboards and visualizations in Power BI and used these insights to enhance the business process

#### **JULY 2019 – AUGUST 2019**

## TRAINING LEAD, GLOBAL TECHNOLOGY COMPANY

- Responsible for development and delivery of global training materials of a new proprietary application on compressed 5 week timeline
- Trainings were developed for 6 workstreams around the globe, with each workstream performing specific functions
- Coordinated requirements gathering meetings with the various workstream leads
- Developed general training as well as specialized trainings for each workstream
- Responsible for scheduling trainings to ensure all trainings were given during relevant time zones
- Delivered weekly status updates to both internal and external stakeholders
- Conducted training sessions across a 2 week timeline, with each day consisting of on average 4-5 hours of training
- Managed 3 onshore resources who helped to prepare and deliver the trainings

#### **DECEMBER 2018 – JUNE 2019**

#### TRAINING MANAGER, GLOBAL TECHNOLOGY COMPANY

- Developed training content and delivered during a weekly training meeting for on average 25 people between offshore and onshore teams
- Met with relevant stakeholders to determine upcoming training needs based on relevant and upcoming technologies
- Worked with the training participants to help deliver more effective training sessions
- Logged relevant questions and followed up as needed
- Worked independently to determine best training practices

## **JUNE 2018 – NOVEMBER 2018**

## TESTING COORDINATOR, GLOBAL PHARMECUTICAL COMPANY

- Developed timeline for testing 300+ applications for compatibility as part of a Windows upgrade
- Coordinated scheduling of testing to ensure adherence to timelines
- Managed 30 physical laptops, and 300 virtual machines for testing applications
- Responsible for device wiping and application install before delivering to the tester
- Worked with testers to create test cases and assisted with troubleshooting
- Developed reporting process and delivered updates to project leadership as needed
- Managed 2 offshore resources

## **EDUCATION**

#### **MAY 2015**

## **BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION – MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEMS,**

#### SAN DIEGO STATE UNIVERSITY

#### Relevant Coursework:

- Managerial Economics
- Statistical Analysis
- Systems Analysis
- Business Law
- Management and Organizational Behavior
- Business Strategy

#### **SEPTEMBER 2023**

## **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP**

#### **UC BERKELEY EXTENSION**

#### Relevant Coursework:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Node.JS
- MySQL
- NoSQL
- MERN

## **SKILLS**

- Project Management
- Relationship Management
- Resource Management (onshore and offshore)
- Budget Management
- Power BI and Data Visualizations
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript

- Resource Planning and Sourcing
- Stakeholder Development
- Program Management
- SCRUM/Agile SDLC
- Azure Dev Ops Administration
- Data Analysis